<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maximilian Dollinger</title>
    <link>https://maxdollinger.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Maximilian Dollinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Maximilian Dollinger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 04:53:38 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maxdollinger.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Polyphasic Sleep: My Adaptation Day 3</title>
      <link>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaption_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 04:53:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaption_3/</guid>
      <description>Today, my adaptation journey went moderately well. In the morning, I was fortunate enough to enjoy a refreshing nap. However, during my second scheduled nap, sleep eluded me. As a result, I found myself battling fatigue throughout the afternoon.
Around midday, a throbbing headache set in, adding to my feelings of misery. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a symptom of the cold turkey caffeine withdrawal. The combination of a headache and tiredness made it difficult to concentrate and enjoy my day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Polyphasic Sleep: My Adaptation Day 2</title>
      <link>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaption_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 05:31:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaption_2/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a concise account of my first day of sleep experimentation:
Despite attempts, I was unable to take a nap on Day 1. Falling asleep during the day proved more difficult than expected. I tried it with progressive muscle relaxation and awareness meditation, but nothing worked.
However, when it came to the core sleep period at 11 p.m., I had no issues drifting off. Interestingly, I awoke at 3:21 AM, nearly 10 minutes before my alarm was due to ring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Polyphasic Sleep: My Adaptation Day 1</title>
      <link>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaption_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 04:58:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaption_1/</guid>
      <description>Being a new parent and trying to balance work, college, and spending time with my little girl has led to an increased need for time. Preferably at night.Polyphasic sleep can help me get the most rest while still having enough time to do my work and spend time with my child.
Polyphasic sleep is a sleep pattern that deviates from the traditional monophasic sleep pattern of one long, continuous period at night.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
