<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maximilian Dollinger</title>
    <link>https://maxdollinger.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Maximilian Dollinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Maximilian Dollinger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 04:48:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maxdollinger.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Polyphasic Sleep: My Adaptation Day 7</title>
      <link>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaptation_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 04:48:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaptation_7/</guid>
      <description>I decided to stick to a 6-hour sleep schedule without incorporating a nap. My fatigue level remained consistent throughout the day without any noticeable changes. Getting up at 4 a.m. feels a bit easier now.
To manage my caffeine intake, I reduced it to half a cup of weak coffee. With that amount, i experienced very mild withdrawal symptoms that were totally manageable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Polyphasic Sleep: My Adaptation Day 6</title>
      <link>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaptation_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 04:48:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaptation_6/</guid>
      <description>Getting up today was decent. I&amp;rsquo;m not feeling exhausted, but I&amp;rsquo;m also not rested. Interestingly, I woke up after 4.5 hours of sleep at 2:30 a.m. and felt ready to get up. Maybe the 4.5-hour core block is more natural for me. Eventually, I will experiment with a biphasic schedule.
Yesterday, I made some positive progress in managing my caffeine withdrawal symptoms. Instead of going cold turkey, I decided to take a more gradual approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Polyphasic Sleep: My Adaptation Day 5</title>
      <link>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaptation_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 04:38:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaptation_5/</guid>
      <description>Caffeine withdrawal can have a significant impact on our well-being, and I experienced this firsthand. Yesterday, the withdrawal symptoms hit me hard, with terrible headaches and overwhelming tiredness. In an effort to cope with this, I decided to switch to the “Everyman 1” sleep schedule.
Under this new schedule, I aimed for 6 hours of core sleep from 22:00 to 4:00, followed by a midday nap. While adjusting to the new routine, I noticed that getting out of bed at 4 a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Polyphasic Sleep: My Adaptation Day 4</title>
      <link>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaptation_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 04:52:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaptation_4/</guid>
      <description>On Day 3, during my first scheduled nap, I found it difficult to fall asleep. Despite feeling tired, my mind seemed to resist the embrace of sleep. However, things took a positive turn during my midday nap. I was able to enjoy a good nap.
Unfortunately, as the day progressed, I again experienced mild headaches during midday and early afternoon. These headaches, combined with a constant feeling of tiredness and weakness, made it challenging to stay focused and productive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Polyphasic Sleep: My Adaptation Day 3</title>
      <link>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaptation_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 04:53:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaptation_3/</guid>
      <description>Today, my adaptation journey went moderately well. In the morning, I was fortunate enough to enjoy a refreshing nap. However, during my second scheduled nap, sleep eluded me. As a result, I found myself battling fatigue throughout the afternoon.
Around midday, a throbbing headache set in, adding to my feelings of misery. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a symptom of the cold turkey caffeine withdrawal. The combination of a headache and tiredness made it difficult to concentrate and enjoy my day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Polyphasic Sleep: My Adaptation Day 2</title>
      <link>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaptation_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 05:31:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaptation_2/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a concise account of my first day of sleep experimentation:
Despite attempts, I was unable to take a nap on Day 1. Falling asleep during the day proved more difficult than expected. I tried it with progressive muscle relaxation and awareness meditation, but nothing worked.
However, when it came to the core sleep period at 11 p.m., I had no issues drifting off. Interestingly, I awoke at 3:21 AM, nearly 10 minutes before my alarm was due to ring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Polyphasic Sleep: My Adaptation Day 1</title>
      <link>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaptation_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 04:58:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxdollinger.github.io/posts/ps_adaptation_1/</guid>
      <description>Being a new parent and trying to balance work, college, and spending time with my little girl has led to an increased need for time. Preferably at night.Polyphasic sleep can help me get the most rest while still having enough time to do my work and spend time with my child.
Polyphasic sleep is a sleep pattern that deviates from the traditional monophasic sleep pattern of one long, continuous period at night.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
